俄罗斯 莫斯科
隧道追击的嫌疑犯正从基辅斯基火车站向东逃离
让他进去
Send him in.
你愿意负责这个计划吗?
Will you commit to this program?
我做不到
I can't.
把手举起来
你愿意负责这个计划吗?
Will you commit to this program?
把手拿出来
你愿意负责这个计划吗?
Will you commit to this program?
我做不到
I can't.
别开枪
我没有武器
把对讲机给我
别杀我
我跟你无仇
片名：《谍影重重3：最后通牒》
六周后
中央情报局 兰利 维吉尼亚州
（爱兹拉·克雷莫 局长 CIA） 你不可能逃出如来佛的手掌
There's no place it won't catch up to you.
所有的故事都是这结局
It's how every story ends.
这就是你的本性 杰森 是个杀手
It's what you are, Jason, a killer.
你永远也无法改变
You always will be.
继续啊！快啊！动手 动手！
Go ahead. Go on. Go on! Do it! Do it!
她不会让我这样做的
She wouldn't want me to.
那是你活着的唯一理由
That's the only reason you're alive.
"她"是指谁?
Who is "she"?
玛丽·克鲁兹 他的女友
Marie Kreutz, his girlfriend.
在印度被杀了
She was killed in India.
是中情局行动主管 华德·艾伯特下的命令
Director of Operations Ward Abbott arranged it.
也就是说 我们的一位无耻主管杀了他女朋友
So we have a dirty section chief who kills Bourne's girl.
伯恩回来报仇 录下了艾伯特供词
Bourne comes back for revenge, tapes Abbott's confession
然后艾伯特自杀了
and Abbott commits suicide.
而现在他来找我们算帐了
Now Bourne's gunning for us.
这些都是事实
You couldn't make this stuff up.
最近发现伯恩的踪影是在莫斯科 六个星期前
Bourne's last confirmed location was Moscow, six weeks ago.
是的 长官
Right. Sir.
他在逃亡中 很危险
He's on the run. He's dangerous.
长官 恕我直言 我认为可能还有其他原因
Well, sir, with respect, I think something else could be going on here.
是什么?他为什么要逃亡?
What? What's he after?
伯恩去莫斯科是为了 找他第一个杀害目标的女儿
The reason Bourne went to Moscow was to see the daughter of his first target.
你的意思是什么 帕梅?
What's your point, Pam?
可能他在回忆他的过去
Maybe he was retracing his steps.
他在寻找某样东西 他回忆里的某样东西
He's looking for something. Something in his past.
也许他还没找到 我们需要知道他在找什么
Maybe he hasn't found it yet and we need to know what it is.
你认为他对我们没有威胁?
Are you telling me he's not a threat to this agency?
我想如果他真的想害我们 大可以把录音带寄到CNN去
I think if he wanted to hurt us, he could have sent the tape to CNN.
也许他会这么做的
Maybe he still will.
我的首要原则就是 抱着最大的希望做最坏的打算
My number one rule is hope for the best, plan for the worst.
对我而言 伯恩始终是个很大的威胁 除非你能证明我错了
As far as I'm concerned, Bourne is still a serious threat until proven otherwise.
继续寻找他的踪影
Let's keep looking.
是 长官 是 长官
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
意大利 都灵
这是三年前的照片 那时有一半的国际刑警都在追捕他
This one's three years ago. They had half of Interpol after him.
后来他曾出现在那不勒斯 柏林 莫斯科
Turned up in Naples, Berlin, Moscow...
然后又消失了
Disappeared again.
与他一起逃亡的女子
The girl that he was on the run with.
玛丽·克鲁兹 尸体在另一半地球的河里被找到
Marie Kreutz. She was found dead in a river halfway round the world.
头部中枪
She'd been shot in the head.
这些都意味着什么?
What connects the dots?
把录音机关掉
Turn off the tape recorder.
法国 巴黎
我妹妹呢?
Where's my sister?
何不先坐下来?
Why don't you sit down?
她在哪里?
Where is she?
她死了
She's dead.
是被杀的
She was killed.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我就知道会是这个结果
I knew this could end this way.
从来就没有过特例
It was always gonna end this way.
我不相信
I didn't believe that.
她怎么死的?
And how did she die?
被枪杀
She was shot.
当时我俩在印度
We were together in India.
那个人的目标是我
He came for me.
你杀了他?
You killed him?
是的
Yes.
现在呢?
And now what?
这一切都起源于某人 我要把他找出来
Someone started all of this and I'm gonna find them.
希思路国际机场 英国 伦敦
喂 是我
Hey. It's me.
是的 他什么都知道
Yeah. He knows the whole story.
伯恩只不过是冰山一角
Bourne's just the tip of the iceberg.
你听说过"黑石楠"计划吗?
Have you heard of an Operation Blackbriar?
我要好好整理一下并写成报道
I'm gonna get my head around this and type it up.
我现在去找你
I'll see you first thing.
好的
Okay.
中情局分局 英国 伦敦
埃施朗电子监测网发现关键词"黑石楠"
Scanning. GoSat 21. I have a hit on ECHELON. Blackbriar.
重复一遍 是"黑石楠"
I repeat, Blackbriar.
信号似乎来自欧洲
Looks like it's coming from a European signal.
国家安全局 请确认
NSA, please confirm your receipt.
（中央情报局 兰利 维吉尼亚州） 我会找到频率和坐标
I'll bring up the frequency and the coordinates
截获我们首要的...
...intercept of our principal...
长官！ 什么情况?
Sir! What you got?
我们截获到了在伦敦的一通电话 内容带有关键词"黑石楠"
We intercepted a call in London. Keyword, "Blackbriar."
好的 马上发给纽约
Okay, send it to New York right away.
中情局掩护机构 反恐局 纽约
跟踪到电话来源了?
Track the phone?
登记者是一位叫 赛门·罗斯的伦敦记者
Registered to a London reporter named Simon Ross.
为《卫报》工作
Works at the Guardian newspaper.
你正在跟踪他吗? 是的 长官！
You're tracking him? Sir. Yeah.
谢谢 麦克
Thanks, Mike.
我们有个调查小组正在跟踪他
We have a survey team covering him at work
另外还派了一组人潜入他的公寓
and a sneak and peek's on their way to his apartment.
他跟谁联系过? 他怎么会知道"黑石楠"计划?
Well, who talked to him? How did he find out about Blackbriar?
我不知道 我们已经调查过他的背景
I don't know. We pulled his background
并且反复确认了所有的疑点
and ran a crosscheck on any known anomalies.
但什么也没有发现 不过我认为只要跟踪罗斯 就能...
We've come up with nothing. But I think if we follow Ross, we're gonna be able...
雷 罗斯不重要 我们要的是消息来源
Ray, Ross is easy. We want the source.
你听说过"黑石楠"计划吗?
Have you heard of an Operation Blackbriar?
你有细节吗?
You have details?
我要好好整理一下并写成报道
I'm gonna get my head around this and type it up.
我现在去找你
I'll see you first thing.
就这些? 是的
Is that all? Yeah.
准备标准行动 为以防万一 让杀手待命
I want rendition protocols and put the asset on standby, just in case.
大家听着 这是4级紧急事件
People, listen up! This is a full priority situation.
吉米 把罗斯的档案投到1号屏上
Jimmy, give me Ross' profile on one.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我们的目标是一位英国记者 赛门·罗斯
Our target is a British national, Simon Ross. A reporter.
我要监视他所有的电话记录 黑莓短讯 公寓 车子
I want all his phones, his BlackBerry, his apartment, his car,
银行账户 信用卡账户 旅行记录
bank accounts, credit cards, travel patterns.
我要在他下一步行动之前 知道他的计划
I want to know what he's gonna think before he does.
我要知道他的一切秘密
Every dirty little secret he has.
最重要的是 我要知道他线人的名字 以及实时位置
And most of all, we want the name and realtime location of his source.
这是国家安全局4级紧急事件 有什么疑问吗?
This is NSA priority level four. Any questions?
好吧 行动
All right, let's get to it.
赛门·罗斯 国际安全事务通讯员
谁是杰森·伯恩? 特别报导之三
德国BND正与南印度警方联手 调查一位德国女性的死亡原因
该名女性疑为伯恩同伙 在其座驾堕桥之后淹死在河里
什么?
What?
你愿意负责这个计划吗?
Will you commit to this program?
我做不到
I can't.
收到 威尔逊先生, 目标正进入办公室
Copy that. Mr. Wills, the subject is entering his office.
给我派几个眼线到街上监视
Give me some eyeballs on the street.
我的现场视频呢?
Where's my picture, please?
快连上了
Coming online.
连上了
Online now.
吉米 电话线那里怎么样?
Jimmy, how you doing with the phone line?
我们已能监听他的办公室电话 现在正在处理手机线路
Yeah, we have an office line. We're working on his cell.
还得花多久 一个小时 长官
How long? An hour, sir.
太慢了
That's too long.
我们怎么知道他是不是受人指使?
So how do we know he's not spinning for someone?
还有更多黑幕 他很害怕
There was more. He was scared.
怕什么? "黑石楠"计划
Scared about what? Blackbriar.
打扰一下 有你的电话 是谁打来的?
Sorry. Call for you. Who is it?
他不肯说
Won't give his name.
抱歉 失陪一下
Excuse me.
在我的线上 谢谢
He's on my line. Thanks.
赛门·罗斯
Simon Ross.
三号摄像头 大屏幕
Camera three, screen.
为什么听不到对话?
Why aren't we hearing this?
吉米 这是座机 为什么我们监听不到?
Jimmy? That's a hard line, Jimmy. Why don't we have it?
我们已经监听了他的线路 但他不在那条线上 他在用别人的电话
We have his line, sir, but he's not on it. He's using a different phone.
我看过你的报道
I've been reading your stories.
你是谁 杰森·伯恩
Who is this? This is Jason Bourne.
滑铁卢车站 南站口 三十分钟后 独自过来
Waterloo Station. South entrance. Thirty minutes. Come alone.
特德 尽快搞定声音信号
Get me audio as soon as you can, Ted.
街道A组、B组
Street teams Alpha, Bravo.
好吧 伙计们 行动 快
Okay, guys, let's work it. Come on.
他去哪里?
Where's he going?
他开始行动了 派一组眼线到街上监视 行动
Okay, he is on the move. Give me eyeballs on the street. Let's go.
滑铁卢车站
目标正离开大楼
Subject exiting the building.
所有人注意 找出他的目的地
All right, everyone, let's find out where he's going.
外勤1号 我需要声音信号
Mobile One, I need audio.
启动声音信号
Audio engaged.
外勤1号跟上他 外勤1号跟上他
Mobile One should have him. Mobile One should have him.
外勤1号跟踪他 听到内容后通知我
Get Mobile One on it. Let me know when you hear it.
滑铁卢车站 南站口
Hi. Waterloo Station, south entrance.
威尔逊先生 他要去哪里?
Mr. Wills.  Where's he going?
目的地是滑铁卢车站
Destination is Waterloo Station.
很好 滑铁卢车站
Okay, Waterloo Station.
马上派眼线前往滑铁卢车站 派出所有人手
Give me eyes at Waterloo. Put everyone in play.
命令杀手行动 调动外勤3号
Let's activate the asset.  Mobilize Tracker Three.
到桥上了吗? 还没有 长官
Are we at the bridge yet?  Not yet, sir.
好的 外勤3号 叫他们与目标保持距离
Okay, Mobile Three, tell them to stay back.
长官
Sir.
请保持监视距离
Please maintain visual contact.
一台预付费手机
Prepaid phone.
给你
Here you go.
外勤1号 请给出目标现在的位置
Mobile One, give me the subject's current location.
收到
Copy that.
长官 目标正在前往 滑铁卢车站的南站口
Sir, the subject is arriving at the south entrance of Waterloo Station.
喂
Hello?
给我传到5号和7号
Give me that on five and seven as well.
吉米 我需要知道电话的内容
Jimmy, I need that phone.
仔细听着我要说的话
I want you to listen very carefully to what I'm about to tell you.
到底发生什么事了?
What the hell's going on?
在你左手边10点钟位置 街道对面 停着一辆银色克莱斯勒旅行车
Ten o'clock, to your left, across the street, there's a silver Chrysler Voyager.
里面是一队监视小组
There's a surveillance team inside.
正前方街道对面 12点位置
Directly across the street, twelve noon,
有个男人在二楼立柱旁
there's a man on the second story, static post.
监视你
He's watching you.
在你左边50米距离外有个公交车站
Now, there's a bus stop 50 meters to your left.
你现在就朝那个方向走去
I want you to walk towards it.
吉米 我需要电话的通话内容！ 昨天就交代了的
Jimmy, I need that phone! I need it yesterday.
他在行动 他在行动
He's on the move. He's on the move.
那不是他的电话 长官
That's not his phone, sir.
再说一遍?
Say again?
那不是他的电话 长官
That's not his phone, sir.
什么叫不是他的电话?
What do you mean that's not his phone?
那部电话是从哪来的?
Where the hell did he get another phone?
嗯 不 你只要...
Well, no, you just have to...
逮捕队B组 准备行动
Grab Team B, stand by.
逮捕队B组 准备就绪
Grab Team B. We're in position.
那里有一个穿蓝色有帽T恤的人
All right, there's a man in a blue hooded sweatshirt.
他正在打电话 走到他的身边 然后停下来
He's talking on a phone. Walk directly to him and stop.
吉米 我们需要通话内容
Jimmy, we need the call. I need that cell phone.
别让他离开视线范围
Do not let him get out of sight.
好的 转过身来
All right, turn around.
那个穿蓝色有帽T恤的家伙是谁?
Okay, who's the guy in the blue hood?
他的联系人吗?
Is that his contact?
有一辆公交车正在靠站 大概10秒钟后会到达
All right, there's a bus coming. It'll be there in ten seconds.
它一停下来 你就开始往左走
When it stops, I want you to walk directly to your left.
那里有个天桥 到楼上的卖报小亭那里去
There's an overpass. Go up the stairs. Stop at the newsstand.
你会在那里得到进一步指示
You'll get further instructions.
好的 好的
Okay. Okay.
准备行动
Get ready to move.
盯着那辆公交 盯着那辆公交
Watch that bus. Watch that bus.
发生什么事了?
What? All right, what's going on?
有谁能告诉我状况 我们失去了一切视频监控
Somebody tell me. We lost the feed. Grab Team B.
逮捕队B组 抓住他的联系人 跟紧罗斯
Intercept the contact and stay with Ross.
嘿！停下！
Hey! Stop!
这里是外勤1号 目标已开始移动
Mobile One. Target's on the move.
他开始移动了 别跟丢了
Okay, he's on the move. Do not lose Ross.
蓝帽子！趴下！马上！
Blue hood! Down! Now!
走 我们走
Go! Let's go.
哦 该死的
Oh, shit.
这是怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
长官 我们失去了与外勤1号的联系
Sir, we've lost all communication with Mobile One.
右边！往西 发现目标后通知我们
To the right! Heading west. Let us know when you get a visual!
最后的所在位置是哪里?
What was the last known position, please?
在通往中央广场的人行道上 长官
On the walkway, heading towards the concourse, sir.
这里是监控队的噩梦 伦敦最忙碌的车站
It's a surveillance nightmare. It's the busiest terminal in London.
接入所有闭路监视系统
Give me all of CCTV's eyes.
正在处理中 长官
On it, sir.
长官 杀手已到现场
Sir, asset's on scene.
你的消息线人是谁?
Who's your source?
他叫什么名字? 你的线人是谁?
What's his name? What's your source's name?
听着 到底发生什么事了? 为什么有一群人在追捕我?
Look, what's going on? Why are these people after me?
因为你知道得太多了
Because you found something.
你与"绊脚石"行动的内部人士沟通过
You talked to someone inside Treadstone.
一个从一开始就参与在其中的人 那个人是谁?
Someone who was there at the beginning. Who is it?
你知道我不能透露
You know I can't tell you that.
你不知道你惹了多大的祸 如果有必要 那些人是会杀人灭口的
You have no idea what you're into here. These people will kill you, if they have to.
是因为"黑石楠"计划吗?
Was it Blackbriar? Is that what this is?
什么"黑石楠"计划?
What's Blackbriar?
"绊脚石"计划的升级版 我的联系人说一切都是从你开始的
Treadstone upgrade. My source told me it all started with you.
他说你是这个肮脏秘密的第一人
He said that you were square one, the dirty little secret.
他说他知道你是谁
He said he knows who you are.
好吧 我们得走了
All right, we have to move.
保持电话联系
Answer your phone.
就要连上了 找到了?
Coming online.  You got visual?
他到底在哪儿?
Where the hell is he, people?
听我的指示 现在走向你的右方
Do exactly as I say. I need you to move up to your right.
右手边第一个电扶梯
First escalator on the right.
马上系鞋带 系鞋带
Tie your shoe. Tie your shoe right now. Tie your shoe.
等着
Wait.
我会从你身边走过 我要你靠着左手边的墙走
I'm gonna walk by you. I want you to move along the far wall
4 3 2 1
to your left in four, three, two, one.
起来
Stand up.
很好
That's it.
他在哪儿?
Where the hell is he?
我们决不能让那家伙失踪
We cannot afford to lose this guy, people.
很好 你现在的方向很好 保持那个方向前进
All right, that line you're on is good. Stay on that line. Stay on that line.
我要去接孩子了 你买完东西了吗?
I've gotta go and pick up the kids. Can you go and get the shopping done?
天啊 那个大块头 我想他是他们的人
Oh, the bin man, I think he's one of them.
那个收垃圾的?不是的
The garbage man? Negative.
天啊 他在拿东西
Oh, Jesus. Jesus! He's reaching for something.
上帝 他有枪 他有枪 保持那个方向
Oh, God, he's got a gun.  Stay on the line.
他有枪 他有枪
He's got a gun. He's got a gun.
保持那个方向 不要往别处走
Stay on the line you're on. Do not deviate.
找到他了！ 他在那儿 他在那儿
Okay, there he is! Here he goes.
逮捕队A组 行动
Grab Team A. Go!
他还在跟某人通话
He's still talking to somebody.
他在接受指令 吉米 给我监听通话内容
He's getting instructions. Jimmy, get me the conversation.
外勤2号 我要... 快 赶快合围
Mobile Two, I want...  Come on, lock the box.
赶快合围 跟进 逮捕队C组
Lock the box. Move in, Grab Team C.
快点 罗斯 我们得走快点
Hurry, Ross. We gotta move.
混入人群 马上混入人群
Okay, move through this crowd. Move through this crowd.
马上隐蔽 混入人群
Get undercover right now. Move through this crowd.
到店里去
Get in the store.
有人在跟踪你 到店里去
There's someone on your tail. Get in the store.
你要从东边的门出来
You're gonna proceed out the east exit.
在你进门的右手边
That's to your right as you come into the store.
进入你前方的酒店
Head into the liquor store in front of you.
然后从后门离开 把门锁上
Go into the back and lock the door.
外勤4号失去联系
Mobile Four is down.
那家伙有帮手 告诉我杀手什么时候能够行动
This guy's got help. Tell me when the asset's in the nest.
我需要里面的信号
Get me a feed in there!
我要逮捕队C组到里面去 告诉我那里发生什么事了
I want Grab Team C in there. Tell me what's going on.
4号队移动
Team Four is mobile.
上帝
Jesus Christ.
是杰森·伯恩
That's Jason Bourne.
他在逐一除掉我们的人 你认为他是线人吗?
He's picking us apart. Do you think he's the source?
一定是他
He's gotta be.
守住所有出口 让杀手行动
Block all the exits. Give the asset a green light.
把他们两个都除掉
Take them both out.
待在那别动
Stay there.
我得想办法突围出去 你得依我的指示行动
I'm gonna get us out of here. You gotta do exactly what I say.
听着 这可不是什么报纸里瞎编的报道
Listen to me! This isn't some story in a newspaper.
这可是真的 明白吗?
This is real. You understand me?
好的
Okay.
让所有特工撤退
Call all agents back.
告诉杀手伯恩的位置：商店后边
Give Bourne's location at the back of the store to the asset.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
支开所有监控摄像头
Kill the cameras.
伯恩 等一下 好像有点不对劲
Bourne. Wait. Something's not right.
我从这里可以看到入口 如果我现在行动 应该能安全逃脱
I can see the entrance from here. If I go now, I can make it.
伯恩
Bourne?
待在那里别动
Just stay where you are.
我们不能等了
I don't think we should wait!
有人在朝这个方向走来
I think someone's coming.
我要拼一把
I'm going for it.
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no!
我们这里出了些状况
We have a situation.
请进
Yeah.
克雷莫局长要见你
Director Kramer would like to see you.
我们要得到许可证...
We need to get those warrants...
他说是紧急事件
He said it's urgent.
什么是"黑石楠"计划?
杰森·伯恩
马德里 西班牙
警方已确认 被害者年龄35岁
What the police will tell me is that they believe the victim is 35yearold
叫赛门·罗斯 是伦敦的一名著名记者
Simon Ross, a wellknown journalist based here in London
供职于《卫报》
with the Guardian newspaper.
现场证据表明他是被枪杀的
It appears that he was gunned down
地点为滑铁卢车站广场
right in the middle of the Waterloo Station concourse
时间约为午后3时45分
around 3:45 this afternoon
有上百位乘客目睹了事件的发生
in full view of hundreds of commuters.
这些年 他揭露了许多不为人知的恐怖事件
Over the years, he's uncovered a lot of
为此 得罪了某些西方国家政府...
that have upset certain Western governments and...
嘿 你好 在那
Hi, how are you? Right over there?
好的
All right.
早上好 先生 您想点些什么?
Good morning, sir. Can I take your order? Yes.
来个煎蛋 奶酪加胡椒粉 谢谢
I'll have the HeartHealthy omelet with goat cheese and peppers, please.
您想要些什么 女士? 咖啡 谢谢
Anything for you, ma'am? Just coffee, please.
只要咖啡?我买单哦
Are you sure? I'm buying.
咖啡就好
I'm good.
局长打来电话 他建议让你加入行动
So, when the Director called and it was suggested that we bring you on...
建议?真的只是建议而已吗?
Suggested? You sure it was just a suggestion?
真有意思
You know, it's funny how different things look
同一件事因所处位置不同 表述的不同 效果也不同
depending on where you sit, right?
在我看来 这对你是个帮助 帕梅
I look at this as a favor for you, Pam,
给你个机会完成你未完成的任务
giving you an opportunity to complete some unfinished business.
什么意思?
Meaning?
伯恩 他在这里 他是个威胁
Bourne. He's here. He's a threat.
而我们 要的是同样的东西
And we both want the same thing.
可是我们获得的手段相去甚远
But we both go about it in two very different ways.
过去的就让它过去吧 帕梅
The past is past, Pam. All right?
斯德哥尔摩的事 我们太大意了
We were careless in Stockholm.
那么滑铁卢站这次 也是大意吗?
So what was Waterloo? Just careless again?
有人泄密 这是非常严重的国家安全问题
We had a leak. A serious national security situation.
伯恩在我们的监视下现身 我们几乎没有时间考虑如何应对
Bourne showed up on our surveillance and we had very little time to react.
一个记者被杀
And a reporter got killed.
伯恩知道我们会行动 关键是 他来这里做什么?
Bourne saw us coming. The question is what was he doing there?
不 关键是
No, the real question is how you managed
你怎么可以让杀手在公共车站射击?
to get into a firefight at a public train station.
你和我都知道 危急状态下 不得不作出欠周全的决定
You know as well as I do decisions made in real time are never perfect.
用不着事后诸葛亮 你这是站着说话不腰疼
Don't secondguess an operation from an armchair.
办公室见
I'll see you at the office.
好好享用你的蛋白
Enjoy your egg whites.
大家注意了
People!
这位是帕梅拉·兰蒂 和她的助手汤姆·克罗宁
This is Pamela Landy and her associate, Tom Cronin.
她将领导这次的搜寻行动
She's gonna be quarterbacking the search effort.
报上你们的名字和职务
Say your names. State your specs, please.
一会儿再报名字吧 伯恩的上一个现身地点是哪?
Well, let's do names later, okay? What's Bourne's last fixed position?
伦敦 12:00
London, 1200 Zulu.
状态?有携带武器吗?受伤否?
Status. What is he? Armed? Wounded?
活着 机动 未知
Alive, mobile and unknown.
申请跨国追踪了吗? 是的
Do we have an ECHELON package?  Yes.
为什么还未启动? 我们在等待
Why isn't it on? We were waiting.
等待?还等什么? 什么... 听着
Waiting? For what? What... Listen,
你们知道自己面对的是什么人吗?
people, do you have any idea who you're dealing with?
这是杰森·伯恩
This is Jason Bourne.
他是你们追踪过的最难对付的人 而你们已经落后了9小时
You are nine hours behind the toughest target you have ever tracked.
我现在要求每个人用上所有注意力 投入百分百精神
Now, I want everyone to sit down, strap in and turn on all you've got.
现在立即行动！
That would mean now!
多谢
Thank you.
给我一支队伍 负责筹划
Give me a team deployment plan.
将罗斯的所有资料放到一号屏幕
I want everything you got on Ross on screen one.
长官 找到了点东西
Sir, I think we have something.
我们截获了罗斯在《卫报》的电邮帐号
We just hacked Ross' email account at the Guardian.
发现昨天前往意大利都灵的来回机票
Found a roundtrip ticket to Turin, Italy, yesterday.
08:00到达 12:05起飞
0800 arrival, 1205 departure.
我们可以确定伯恩不是他的线人
I think we can be pretty certain that Bourne's not your source, then.
为什么?
How?
罗斯刚下都灵飞回伦敦的飞机
Ross's call to his editor where he said he'd just met the source
就打电话给他的编辑说他刚见过他的线人
took place just after his Turin flight landed.
说明他在都灵跟线人会了面 那么?
He met his source in Turin. So?
什么? 难道伯恩和罗斯先在都灵共进早餐
What? So, what? Bourne met Ross in Turin for breakfast
然后又在同一天约在滑铁卢车站会面?
and then at noon the same day Bourne calls Ross to demand a meet at Waterloo?
说不定他们还乘坐同一班飞机呢
Maybe they were even on the same flight.
看看都有什么
Pull up everything you've got.
核对所有CIA内部登记的手机使用情况
Crosscheck the secure cell phone usage of everyone with SCI clearance
追查罗斯在都灵的时间内 所有打入和打出的电话
against all calls going in and out of Turin, Italy, the morning Ross was there.
你要找的人是CIA特工 他掌握了高度机密
This guy you're after is a CIA operative with clearance above top secret.
他与罗斯的谈话是叛国行为
He's committing treason by talking to Ross.
那么他既然知道我们
Do you really think while doing that
可以追踪到他的手机 还会用手机联络吗?
he's gonna use a cell phone that he knows we can track?
没有查到任何记录
Zero results on the crosscheck.
那你有什么高见?
So, you got any better ideas?
查询罗斯在都灵整个期间
Yeah, look at all the people whose cell phones were switched off
所有关闭手机的人
the entire period Ross was in Turin.
如果大家都像我一样经常打电话
I mean, if your people are on their phones as much as mine,
那么关机的人数应该不多
the list should be pretty small.
三个人：汤姆·布鲁斯特 杰克·布林以及尼尔·丹尼而斯
Three names. Tom Brewster, Jack Boulin and Neal Daniels.
查询罗斯住处所有与这三个人有关的资料
Okay, now check everything in Ross' apartment against those names.
找共同点
Check for common patterns.
找任何罗斯与人会面的线索
Look for anything that indicates who Ross met.
放大他的单子 放大
Pull up his socials. Pull it up.
看到文件了吗?
See those documents?
停
CRONIN: Break it.
那是什么?
Over here. What is that?
就是那里 名字开头字母
All right. Right there. Initials.
放大 放到大屏幕上
Pull that up. Bring that up on main.
尼尔·丹尼尔斯
Neal Daniels.
他不是我们在马德里分站的头子吗?
He's station chief in Madrid, isn't he?
是的
Yeah.
通知大使馆的安全官
All right, call the RSO at the embassy.
如果丹尼尔斯在那里 收押他
Have them take Daniels into custody, if he is there.
安娜 派人到卡里诺特街的藏身处
Anna, get grab teams to the Calle Norte safe house.
让他们全副武装 告诉他们我们会帮忙封锁所有入口的
Send them in heavy. Tell them we'll assist with the entry.
全副武装?丹尼尔斯不是...
Heavy? Daniels isn't really that much of a...
我担心的是伯恩
I'm worried about Bourne.
如果他不是线人
If he is not the source,
那么他就是在追踪这个线人 与我们一样
then he is after the source, the same as we are.
二队什么时候到?
ETA, Team Two.
长官 3分钟后抵达
Three minutes to destination, sir.
你将拯救美国人民的生命
Your mission will save American lives.
献身这个计划
Really give yourself to this program.
我做不到
I can't.
你能做到
You can.
长官 他们已经到达正门
Sir, they're at the front door.
5秒钟 实时监控
Five seconds. Put it up live.
已经进入
We're in.
防盗铃被毁坏
The alarm's down.
一定是伯恩
That's gotta be Bourne.
保险箱空了 靠
The safe is empty. Shit.
貌似他匆忙离开的
Looks like he left in a hurry.
监控丹尼尔斯的护照
Track Daniels' passports.
行动
Stand by.
哈蒙德
Hammond.
该死的！派后援部队！
God damn it! Get a backup team in there!
给我派上后卫队 立即派上另一队
Get me a secure line in there. Get the second team over there now!
你来这儿做什么?
What are you doing here?
柏林行动之后 我就被派到这里
I was posted here after Berlin.
丹尼尔斯在哪?
Where's Daniels?
他在哪?
Where is he?
喂?
Hello?
哪位?
Who is this?
我是妮可·帕森
This is Nicky Parsons.
她是"绊脚石"计划的后勤
She was Treadstone. Logistics.
在柏林追捕伯恩时 她也在
She was with us when we hunted Bourne in Berlin.
妮可 我需要进行身份核对
Nicky, I need to do an ID challenge.
密码是麻雀
Code in, Sparrow.
（危险回应：红宝石）
回应是珠穆朗玛峰
Response, Everest.
（正常回应：珠穆朗玛峰）
妮可 我是诺亚·沃森 你到现场多久了?
Nicky, this is Noah Vosen. How long have you been onsite?
我刚进来
I just walked in.
在现场有我们两名同伴 你看到他们了吗?
We have two officers onsite. Are you in contact with them?
他们被放倒了 不省人事 不过还活着
They're down. Unconscious but alive.
见到尼尔·丹尼尔斯吗?
Any sign of Neal Daniels?
没有
No.
妮可 我是帕梅·兰蒂
Nicky, this is Pam Landy.
我们有理由相信
We have reason to believe there's a connection between
尼尔·丹尼尔斯与杰森·伯恩有关联
Neal Daniels and Jason Bourne.
伯恩?你仍在找伯恩? 我以为那个行动已经终结了
Bourne? You're still looking for Bourne? I thought that case was closed.
不 有人坚信他仍然是个威胁
No, some people are convinced he's still a threat.
我不这么认为 不过我必须与他谈谈 才能知道真相
I disagree, but to find out I need to talk to him.
等一下 妮可
Hold on, Nicky.
你这是在干什么? 我想给他传达一个信息
What the hell are you doing? I'm trying to send him a message.
你认为伯恩不是威胁? 他刚又放倒两个我的人
You don't think Bourne is a threat? He just took out two more of my men.
唯一妥善解决这件事的方法
The only way this has a happy ending, Noah,
就是把他活捉
is if we bring him in alive.
他在追踪丹尼尔斯
He is going after Daniels.
他想复仇 帕梅 结束这一切的唯一办法
He wants revenge, Pam, and the only realistic way
就是解除威胁
to end this is to eliminate the threat.
后援什么时候能到?
How long until backup?
妮可 请你留在原地 保护现场
Nicky, I need you to stay put and secure the premises.
后援将在一小时之后到达 明白吗?
Backup will be arriving in approximately one hour. Do you copy?
收到 长官
Copy, sir.
我有多长时间?
How long do I have?
3分钟
Three minutes.
我的车在外面
My car's outside.
我知道丹尼尔斯在哪儿
I know where Daniels is.
这里是卡里诺特街334号 刚听到抢响 有人喊叫 应该是美国人
快
Come on.
2分钟后抵达 长官
Two minutes to destination, sir.
逮捕队A组和B组...
Grab Teams A and B...
丹尼尔斯在哪儿?
Where was Daniels headed?
今早8点 他电汇了十万美元到丹吉尔的一个银行帐户
At 8:00 this morning, he wired $100,000 to a bank account in Tangier.
离这里300英里 如果加快速度 我们能赶得上早班轮船
Right, that's 300 miles away. If we hurry, we can make the morning ferry.
你的车停在哪?
Where are you parked?
右边 离北街20米
To the right, 20 meters, north side of the street.
他们来了
They're coming.
继续走
Keep moving.
两个目标从藏身处出来
Two subjects seen exiting safe house.
这是怎么回事?
What the hell is this?
不 不 等等
Wait, wait, wait! No, no, no!
到底怎么回事?
What the hell just happened?
目标行踪丢失 长官
We've lost visual contact with the subjects, sir.
天哪
Christ!
下达指示 对伯恩格杀勿论 即刻生效
Issue a standing kill order on Jason Bourne, effective immediately.
联系西班牙方面
Send out a system one alert to all Spanish contacts.
进行全面封锁
I want all air and ground border exits locked down.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
丹尼尔斯手上到底有什么?
What's Daniels got?
"黑石楠"计划又是什么?
What's Operation Blackbriar?
是你自己告诉我 还是我打电话问克雷莫?
Do you want to tell me, or should I call Kramer and ask him?
老天哪 帕梅 这可是在行动中
For Christ's sake, Pam, we're in the middle of an operation.
胡说八道
Bullshit.
你要杰森·伯恩?
You want Jason Bourne,
跟我说实话
level with me.
"黑石楠"计划一开始是监视计划
Operation Blackbriar started as an NEAT surveillance program.
那么现在是什么?
And what is it now?
现在它是作为保护伞 掩护我们所有幕后行动
It is now the umbrella program for all our black ops.
包括侵入 押送 试验性审问
Full envelope intrusion, rendition, experimental interrogation
全部由这个办公室发出指令
is all run out of this office.
我们是金字塔的顶端 帕梅
We are the sharp end of the stick now, Pam.
包括杀害行动?
Lethal action?
在必要的时候 是的
If we have to, sure.
正因如此 我们才特别 无需许可证
That's what makes us special. No more red tape.
再不用为了等华盛顿签署命令
No more getting the bad guys caught in our sights,then watching them escape
眼睁睁看着坏蛋从眼前逃走
while we wait for someone in Washington to issue the order.
拜托
Oh, come on.
帕梅 你大场面见过不少 你知道他们有多么危险
You've seen the raw intel, Pam. You know how real the danger is.
我们需要这样的行动
We need these programs now.
丹尼尔斯跟这个有什么关系?
What's the connection to Daniels?
我们在南欧以及北非的所有行动都由他负责
He ran all of our operations in Southern Europe and North Africa,
他掌握着所有资料
so he has everything.
名字 日期 我们在海外的联系人
Names, dates, ghost sites, who's cooperating with us abroad.
每一个行动
Every operation.
你想让这些落入伯恩手中 然后流入市场吗?
You want that stuff in Bourne's hands, out on the market to the highest bidder?
应该不会吧
I don't think so.
伯恩不是为了钱 他为了某个原因要找丹尼尔斯
Bourne's not after money. He's after Daniels for a reason.
嗯 管他伯恩想找什么呢
Well, what does it matter what Bourne is after?
相信我 只要找到丹尼尔斯 我们就能找到他
When we find Daniels, and, believe me, we'll find him,
如果你说得没错
if you're right,
伯恩也会在我们手上
we get Bourne, too.
你为什么要回来?
Why did you come back?
你为什么要找丹尼尔斯?
Why are you looking for Daniels?
你知道这个是谁吗?
Do you know who that is?
这个是丹尼尔斯
That's Daniels.
我不知道另外一个是谁 他是谁?
I don't know who that is. Who is he?
他一开始就在场
He was there at the beginning.
我记得自己见过他
I remember meeting him.
第一天
The first day.
丹尼尔斯带我去见他
Daniels brought me to him.
就是从那里开始的
That's where it all started for me.
在我身上发生了一些事 我需要知道是什么
Something happened to me and I need to know what it was
否则我永远无法摆脱
or I'll never be free of this.
丹尼尔斯说 对你的训练是试验性质的
Daniels said the training was experimental.
行为修正
Behavior modification.
必须先让特工瓦解 然后他们才能负责行动
They had to break down the agents before they became operational.
他说你是第一个
He said you were the first one.
你为什么要帮我?
Why are you helping me?
与你在一起 对我来说 很困难
It was difficult for me with you.
你真的什么也不记得了?
You really don't remember anything.
不记得
No.
我们得走了
We have to move.
（尼尔·丹尼尔斯护照追踪 锁定）
长官 威尔逊先生 你应该看看这个
Sir? Mr. Wills? You're gonna want to look at this.
他在丹吉尔
He's in Tangier.
诺亚·沃森
Noah Vosen.
我们找到丹尼尔斯了
We have found Daniels.
他们查到了他在丹吉尔的一个旅馆里 用了他的护照
They've just tracked Daniels' passport to a hotel in Tangier.
他们借故拖延丹尼尔斯的银行转帐
They're holding up a bank transfer he made to keep him in place
同时从卡萨布兰卡派出了杀手
while they bring an asset up from Casablanca.
他们要干掉他
They're gonna take him out.
什么事?
Yeah.
帕梅拉·兰蒂 她说有紧急情况
It's Pam Landy. She says it's urgent.
告诉她我没空
Tell her I'm unavailable.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
摩洛哥 丹吉尔
长官 杀手已经到达机场
Sir, asset has arrived at the airport.
告诉我目标位置
Give me the subject's location.
目标徒步 正进入莫拉博斯旅馆
Subject is now on foot and entering Hotel Velasquez.
旅馆距离银行2.2公里
Hotel is 2.2 kilometers from the bank.
给出旅馆正面图 平面图 一间间找
All right, get an elevation and a floor plan, tictactoe.
找出房间位置
Locate the room.
告诉杀手房间位置
Give the asset subject location
以及旅馆到银行的路线图
and the route between the subject's hotel and the bank.
房间位置确定了吗?
Do we have that room yet?
是的 长官 117号房间
Yes, sir. It's room 117.
掌握旅馆总线
All right, get a hold of the hotel trunk line.
监控旅馆117号房间.
Run all calls through here with an ISO on room 117.
他的位置被防火墙阻挡
His location's being blocked by the firewall.
不 他们已经找到丹尼尔斯了 也知道他在哪儿
No, they found Daniels. They know where he is.
他们派出杀手去解决他
They'll get one of the operatives to terminate him.
把杀手找出来
Find out who.
戴仕
Desh.
告诉他你要见他 说你要给他一部新手机
Tell him you're gonna meet him and you have a new phone for him.
如果你阻止了戴仕 他们也会找别人的
If you stop Desh, they'll just get someone else.
我们不是要阻止他 而是要跟踪他
No, we're not gonna stop him, we're gonna follow him.
他会带领我们找到丹尼尔斯
He'll take us right to Daniels.
长官 杀手背离了预定路线
Sir, the asset is deviating off course.
让他去
Let it play.
杀手意外停止行动
Asset unscheduled stop.
长官 杀手正在向目标移动
Sir, asset is on the move en route to subject.
长官 有人未经授权
Sir, we have an unauthorized breach.
侵入我们的网络
Someone with active system knowledge penetrated our protocol.
在当地时间14:11向杀手发送指令
Instructions were sent to the asset at 1411 local time.
指令是有效的
Trace is confirmed and valid.
是通过妮可·帕森注册的计算机
It came from a computer belonging to Nicky Parsons.
背离发生在哪个地点?
Where did the course deviation occur?
贝尔基路南面 过了佛郎路
South to Rue de Belgique, stationary Place de France.
帕森就在那
That's where Parsons is.
解决丹尼尔斯之后 让杀手解决妮可
When we're finished with Daniels, send the asset after her.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
找到帕森 找到伯恩
We find Parsons, we find Bourne.
诺亚 你这是干什么?
Noah, what are you doing?
现在不是时候 我需要知道 到底是怎么回事
Not now. I wanna know what's going on.
我说了现在不是时候
I said not now!
你依据什么发布这个指令?
What basis are you continuing this operation on?
我的依据就是 妮可已经危及我们的隐蔽行动
On the basis that Nicky Parsons has compromised a covert operation.
她把我们置于不利境地
She is up to her neck in this!
这个行动是针对丹尼尔斯的 不是妮可
This is about Daniels, not Nicky!
她背叛了我们
She has betrayed us.
你根本不知道情况 诺亚
You don't know the circumstances, Noah.
天哪 她现在跟伯恩一条战线
She's in league with Jason Bourne, for Christ's sakes!
你无权杀死她
You do not have the authority to kill her!
哦 我有权 你最好识点时务
Oh, yes, I do. And you had better get on board.
诺亚 她是我们的人
Noah, she's one of us.
你一旦走出这一步 将要如何收场?
You start down this path, where does it end?
我们获胜的时候就是收场的时候
It ends when we've won.
解决丹尼尔斯之后 让杀手干掉他俩
When we're finished with Daniels, send the asset after them.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
好了 快点 行动
Okay, come on. Stand by...
2分钟 长官 2分钟
Two minutes, sir. Two minutes.
告诉银行解除电汇冻结
Tell the bank to release the funds.
你好
Hello?
钱已经到帐
他正离开
He's on the move.
他已经到位
On it, sir.
200米
Two hundred meters.
快点 我应该多准备点跟踪摄像头
Okay, come on, I want to lay in some preliminary tracking.
停车
Stop!
发密信 就说我们死了
Code it in. We need to be dead.
先生 杀手证实两个目标都已经被消灭
Sir? Asset confirms both targets are down.
活要见人 死要见尸
I want to be sure about this.
让拉巴特的站长确认死亡
Ask the station chief from Rabat to confirm the deaths
秘密搜寻尸首
and do a subrosa collection of the bodies.
我要求这件事万无一失
I want to tie this thing off completely.
小心监视兰蒂
And keep an eye on Landy.
什么事?
Yeah?
伯恩和妮可·帕森都死了
Bourne and Nicky Parsons are dead.
你确定吗?
You sure about that?
拉巴特的站长正在核实
Our station chief in Rabat is confirming.
绝对不能让我暴露
I can't afford to have this come back to me.
不用担心 你是受保护的
Don't worry. You're protected.
一定记住我们派兰蒂到你那里的原因
Just remember why we put Landy there.
如果"黑石楠"计划泄露
If Blackbriar goes south,
我们就卷铺盖走人重新来过
we'll roll it up, hang it around her neck and start over.
我能看到他们的脸
I can see their faces.
我杀过的每一个人
Everyone I ever killed.
只是不知道他们的名字
I just don't know their names.
玛丽过去常常...
Marie used to try to
...帮助我回忆他们的名字
help me remember the names.
"任务中止"
目标：尼瓦纳·瓦博斯 国籍：尼日利亚
执行人：杰森·伯恩 "绊脚石计划" 结果：失败
我想为我做过的…
I've tried to apologize for...
做过的一切道歉
For what I've done.
为我现在做的事情道歉
For what I am.
但是我的心依然沉重
None of it makes it any better.
他们会继续追杀你
They're gonna come for you again.
你必须马上逃亡
You're gonna have to run now.
"绊脚石"计划 杰森·伯恩
实验对象表现出反抗迹象
阿尔伯特·赫斯医生授权…
阿尔伯特·赫斯医生 职位：首席医务官
对象在99年6月1日被送到纽约 东71街415号"绊脚石"特别治疗部门
特别研究部指导训练官 尼尔·丹尼尔斯记录
我们该出发了
We should go.
事情会好起来的
It gets easier.
丹尼尔斯先生的东西都在这儿
所有的吗?
是的
打开看看
中央情报局 纽约40街105号
纽约
情报站站长奥玛巴刚打电话过来
Station chief in Rabat just called.
他们找到了尸体
They found a body.
伯恩? 戴仕
Bourne? Desh.
帕梅 你应该看看这个
Pam. You need to see this.
一个叫吉尔波特·皮安特的人 刚入境
A passport for Gilberto de Piento just cleared immigration.
这是"绊脚石"计划中 杰森·伯恩的化名之一
It's an early Treadstone identity registered to Jason Bourne,
他从来没有使用过这个化名 这个化名也从来没有浮现过
but he never used it, and it never went to the grid.
伯恩还活着
Bourne's alive.
他们不知道吗?
They don't know?
如果知道 他们现在就不会呆在这里
Well, if they knew, Vosen wouldn't be in his office right now.
他真是冒了极大风险
It's a hell of a risk.
也许伯恩就是想让我们知道
Maybe Bourne wants us to know.
就像上次在那不勒斯一样 也许他在和我们联系
Just like Naples. Maybe he's communicating.
也许他在联系你
Maybe he's trying to communicate with you.
那么我们应该回复
Then we should communicate back.
我想我知道伯恩在寻找什么
I think I know what Bourne's looking for.
吉尔波特·皮安特 吉尔波特·皮安特
Gilberto de Piento. Gilberto de Piento.
你的伙伴在等你
Your party is waiting for you.
帕梅拉·兰蒂
Pamela Landy.
我听说你还在找我
I hear you're still looking for me.
伯恩?
Bourne?
你想怎么样?
What do you want?
什么事?
Yeah?
你最好过来 我们发现了新情况
Better get in here. We got a situation.
我…
I...
我想...谢谢你提供的录音带
I wanted to thank you for the tape.
事情已经全部解决了
It's all tied off. It's over.
我想我应该对你道歉
I guess I owe you an apology.
是官方的吗?
Is that official?
不 非官方的 你知道原委的
No. Off the record. You know how it is.
追踪结果?
You tracing this?
还要50秒
Fifty seconds to trace.
再见 等等
Goodbye. Wait. Wait.
戴维·韦伯 是你的真名
David Webb. That's your real name.
你生于71年4月15日 密苏里州尼克斯
You were born 4/15/71 in Nixa, Missouri.
为什么不过来 我们好好谈谈?
Why don't you come in and we'll talk about it?
这里面绝对有问题
Something is very wrong here.
伯恩?
Bourne?
好好休息一下 帕梅
Get some rest, Pam.
你看起来很疲倦
You look tired.
他在看着她
He's looking right at her.
大家听好
People, listen up!
这是国家安全的紧急情况
This is a national security emergency.
我们即将受到严重威胁
We have an imminent threat.
我要出去
I'm going out there.
我现身 他就会找到我
If I show myself, he'll find me.
杰森·伯恩还活着 就在纽约
Jason Bourne is alive and is at large in New York City,
相信就在我们周围方圆1000码
and, we believe, within 1,000 yards of this building.
我要求马上封闭周围12个街区
I want an immediate 12block lockdown of the area.
马上通知兰利总部
Send a flash message to Langley.
启动本地后备系统
Prep for local backup assistance.
兰蒂刚离开大楼
Landy just left the building!
窃听她的电话
Stay with her phone.
她正在用手机收短信
She's using her cell. There's an incoming text.
我要短信内容 正在获取 先生
Get it.  Working on it, sir.
我们有几个人跟踪兰蒂?
How many do we have on Landy?
6个 还有后援正在到达
Six men. More on the way.
我收到了 先生 现在就显示到屏幕上
I've got it, sir! Coming up on the screen now.
都铎城路和42街 10分钟后 单独见面
跟踪兰蒂的所有人 马上去都铎城路
Anybody not on Landy goes directly to Tudor City.
准备车辆 我们上车指挥
Get the vehicles. We're going mobile.
第二组 第二组 所有小组集合
Team Two. Team Two. All teams, call in.
178号
178th.
那是一个死胡同 他为什么要这么做?
There's only one way out of there. Why would he do that?
他在困住自己
He's trapping himself.
不是一个会面的好地点 太显眼了
It's a bad place to meet. It's too exposed.
他选这个地方一定有他的理由
He wouldn't have chosen it if he didn't have a reason.
目标还在行进
Subject is en route.
屋顶43 看到目标通知我们
Roof 43, let me know when you have visual.
屋顶43 随时待命
Roof 43, standing by.
待命
Standing by.
好 我们现在行动 覆盖周围200米
Okay, folks, here we go. Box 200 meters.
已就位
Visual on leader.
地面43号就位
43 ground in position.
你们一看到兰蒂 马上通知我
As soon as you have eyes on Landy, I wanna know.
好 她来了
Okay, here we go.
收到 我也看到她了
Copy that. I see her.
有伯恩的迹象吗?
Any sign of Bourne?
没有
Negative.
没有发现目标
No sign of target.
诺亚·沃森
Noah Vosen.
我是杰森·伯恩
This is Jason Bourne.
我还在想你什么时候能给我打电话
I was wondering when you were going to make this call.
你怎么得到这个号码的?
How did you get this number?
你不会真以为我去都铎城路吧
You didn't actually think I was coming to Tudor City, did you?
我没这么想
No, I guess not.
但是如果你想跟我谈
But if it's me you want to talk to,
也许我们可以安排一个会面地点
perhaps we can arrange a meet.
你现在在哪?
Where are you now?
我在我的办公室
I'm sitting in my office.
我不信
I doubt that.
你为什么不信?
And why would you doubt that?
如果你现在就在办公室
If you were in your office right now,
那么我们就是在面对面谈话
we'd be having this conversation face to face.
诺亚·沃森
Noah Vosen.
密码10取消行动
This is a code ten abort.
所有人回到车上 密码10取消行动
I want everyone back in the vehicles. This is a code ten abort.
快走！快走！
Let's go! Let's go!
绝密：黑石楠计划
"绊脚石"计划升级到"黑石楠"计划
被杀 机密：美国公民
什么事?
Yeah?
威尔森 马上检查我的办公室
Wills, check my office.
见鬼！
Damn it!
怎么回事?
What's going on?
让保安到这来
We need building security up here.
他拿走了全部档案 妈的！
He's got everything. God damn it!
封锁大楼周围4个街区
All right, set a fourblock perimeter around the building.
我们要发现目标
Somebody give me a visual.
我要求整座大楼都被搜查
I want the entire building searched.
每个房间 每个走廊 每个壁橱 每个通风道
Every room, every hallway, every closet, every goddamn air duct.
明白吗?我要你们找到他！
You understand? I want him found!
发生什么事了?
What just happened?
伯恩进入大楼 打开了沃森的保险柜
Bourne just broke into CRI. He got into Vosen's safe.
去哪儿?
Where to?
东71街415号
415 East 71st Street.
71街415号?天啊 帕梅
Fourfifteenseventyone? Jesus, Pam.
发现目标
Target in sight.
目标向北转入第8大道
North on Eighth.
目标进入港务局
He's headed east in the Port Authority.
授权所有特工 可以格杀勿论
All agents have shootonsight authorization.
在那！
Right there!
先生 他开下房顶了 什么?
Sir, he drove off the roof. What?
他开下房顶了！
He drove off the roof!
他下车了 现在在跑
He's on foot. He's running.
警察！不许动！
Police! Freeze!
举起手来！
Put your hands in the air!
叫后援！
Call for backup!
先生 你看 伯恩的生日 先生
Sir, sir, take a look at this! Bourne's birthday, sir.
有什么问题? 请看 先生
What about it? Check that out.
兰蒂告诉伯恩他的生日是71年4月15号
Sir, Landy told Bourne that his birthday was 4l15l71.
她告诉他的是一个密码
Oh, my God. It's a code.
都停下手头的工作！听着！
Everything stops. Everything stops! Listen up!
4/15/71 新的任务
4l15l71. New assignment, numbers.
这组数字是什么意思?快解码！
What does it mean? Give me encryption codes!
先生 转换成经纬度
Sir, if you plug them in as variables of longitude and latitude
就是喀麦隆
you get Cameroon.
41571是肯塔基州瓦尔尼的邮政编码
41571 is the zip code for Varney, Kentucky.
她给的是什么数字?
What date did she give him?
4/15/71
4/15/71.
我真不敢相信
I don't believe it.
这组号码表示东71街415号
SRD is at 415 East 71st Street.
她告诉了他训练中心的地址
She just gave him the training facility.
哦 天啊
Oh, Christ.
所有小组跟着我
Bring all the teams in behind us.
快！报警！
Hurry up! Somebody call 911!
救救他！
Help him!
先生 特工没有杀掉伯恩 我们也跟丢了
The asset lost Bourne. We lost him.
阿尔伯特 我是沃森
Hello? Albert, it's Vosen.
伯恩知道了一切 他正在去你那儿
Bourne knows everything and he's on his way to you right now.
他要回家了
He's coming home, Noah.
我还有多长时间?
How long do I have?
我不知道
I don't know.
你赶快跑吧
Just get the hell out of there.
不 我要留下
No, I'm gonna stay.
他会来训练中心一侧 那是他以前待过的地方
He'll head for the training wing. That's what he knows.
我会稳住他 直到你赶来
I'll keep him in play till you get there.
你给了我这些 他们会杀了你
They'll kill you for giving me this.
4/15/71也不算密码
4l15l71 isn't much of a code.
我猜沃森已经赶过来了
My guess is Vosen is on his way already.
你为什么这么做?
Why'd you do it?
因为那不是我的工作
Because this isn't what I signed up for,
他们对你做了这些 "黑石楠"计划
what they did to you, Blackbriar.
不是我们
This isn't us.
那么你就做点什么吧 你需要的都在里面
Then do something about it. Everything you need is in there.
所有一切
Everything.
戴维 何不和我一起进去?
David. Why don't you come in with me?
我们一起去会更好
It'll be better if we do this together.
不
No.
这里是我开始的地方
This is where it started for me.
也是结束的地方
This is where it ends.
是兰蒂
That's Landy.
封锁这座大楼
All right, lock this building down.
周围1个街区警戒
Set a secure perimeter of one block.
你好 我是帕梅拉·兰蒂 我要发送机密文件
Hello. This is Pamela Landy. I have to send a classified document.
派一个小组去追伯恩
Get a team to SRD after Bourne.
其他人派到这个医院的所有公共区域
And put someone in every public area of this hospital.
电梯间 员工电梯 快！
Okay. Elevator shafts, service entrances, go!
见鬼！南边的电梯 快！
Damn it! South bay! Go!
先生们 这是紧急情况
Gentlemen, this is a priority one situation!
要求你们的完全合作
You will give us your full cooperation.
给我看过去3分钟大厦的全部监视录像
Give me playback for the entire building for the last three minutes.
是的 显示
Yes, sir.
快！快！
Move! Move!
这个！这是哪里?
This one, here! Where is this?
一楼
First floor.
我自己去抓兰蒂
I'll take Landy on my own.
你最好找个好律师
You better get yourself a good lawyer.
剃刀边缘有个共和国
A republic lives on the knife's edge.
我们完成后 你就不再是戴维·韦伯
When we are finished with you, you will no longer be David Webb.
你甚至记不得那个名字是谁
You may not even remember who he was.
你知道为什么我们这么对待你吗?
You know why we're treating you like this?
你好 杰森
Hello, Jason.
我相信你是遇到了一些问题
I believe you've been having some problems.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
如果我不想谈的话就不会到这来了
I wouldn't be here if I didn't want to talk.
我过去三年一直在逃亡
I've spent three years running.
三年来一直想知道自己是谁
Three years trying to find out who I am.
你还是记不起来 对吧?
You've still not got it all back, have you?
破碎的记忆难以拼凑
Still not filled in the pieces.
一直都是你
It was always you.
我没有武器 杰森
I'm unarmed, Jason.
为什么是我? 你为什么要选我?
Why me? Why did you pick me?
你真的记不起来 是不是?
Your really don't remember, do you?
不是我们选择你 而是你选择了我们
We didn't pick you. You picked us.
你是自愿的
You volunteered.
就在这里
Right here.
即使我们已经警告了你
Even after you were warned.
韦伯上尉
Captain Webb.
早上好 上尉
Good morning, Captain.
你来到这
You came in here.
眼睛都没眨 杰森
You didn't even blink, Jason.
你把这个递给了我
You just handed me these.
戴维·韦伯
所有的事情都对你解释了吗?
Has everything been explained to you?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
你说你想报效国家
You said you wanted to serve.
你的任务会拯救美国公民的生命
Your missions will save American lives.
我知道 先生
WEBB: I understand, sir.
你说过我会拯救美国公民的生命
You said I'd be saving American lives.
你确实是这样
You were.
我是在替你杀人
I was killing for you.
替他们杀人
For them.
你完全知道你选择留下 意味着什么
You knew exactly what it meant for you if you chose to stay.
我们完成后 你就不再是戴维·韦伯
When we are finished with you, you will no longer be David Webb.
你让我成为谁 我就成为谁 先生
I'll be whoever you need me to be, sir.
你不能逃避你做过的事 杰森
You can't outrun what you did, Jason.
你让自己成为了后来的你
You made yourself into who you are.
最终你必须面对现实
Eventually you're gonna have to face the fact
是你在这里选择成为了杰森·伯恩
you chose right here to become Jason Bourne.
你很久没有睡觉了
You haven't slept for a long time.
你决定了吗?
Have you made a decision?
这样没法继续
This can't go on.
你必须现在决定
You have to decide.
他是谁?
Who is he?
我们已经讨论过了
We've been through that.
他做了什么?
What did he do?
那并不重要
It doesn't matter.
你找到我们
You came to us.
你是自愿的
You volunteered.
你说你会做任何事
You said you'd do anything it takes to
来拯救美国公民的生命
save American lives.
你不是在说谎 对不对?
You're not a liar, are you?
或者太软弱
Or too weak
不能胜任?
to see this through?
就这样
This is it.
忘掉戴维·韦伯
Let go of David Webb.
献身这个计划
Really give yourself to this program.
你不再是
You're no longer
戴维·韦伯
David Webb.
从现在起 你就是杰森·伯恩
From now on, you'll be known as Jason Bourne.
欢迎加入这个计划
Welcome to the program.
你现在记起来了?
Do you remember now?
我记起来了
I remember.
我记起来一切
I remember everything.
我再也不是杰森·伯恩
I'm no longer Jason Bourne.
那么你会杀我吗
So now you're gonna kill me.
不
No.
你根本不配挂在兰利墙上的星星
You don't deserve the star they'd give you on the wall at Langley.
他去屋顶了！
He's headed for the roof!
你为什么没有开枪?
Why didn't you take the shot?
你知道为什么要杀我吗?
Do you even know why you're supposed to kill me?
看看我们自己
Look at us.
看看他们让你付出的是什么
Look at what they make you give.
早上好 参议员们
Good morning, senators.
请允许我先发表一个声明
If I may, I'd like to begin by making a statement for the record.
文件显示爱兹拉·克雷莫 授权6项非法的…
The file indicates that Ezra Kramer authorized six illegal...
总统今天
The President convened
召开紧急内阁会议
an emergency cabinet meeting today
讨论越来越多的
to discuss the growing scandal
政府涉嫌暗杀行动的丑闻
over an alleged government assassination program,
行动代号"黑石楠"
codenamed Blackbriar.
CIA局长爱兹拉·克雷莫因为授权此行动
CIA Director Ezra Kramer is under criminal investigation
受到司法调查
for authorizing the program,
其中几起涉及到杀害美国公民
which in several cases may have even targeted US citizens.
两个CIA的高级官员已被逮捕
Two agency officials have already been arrested.
阿尔伯特·赫斯医生 "黑石楠"计划的策划者
Dr. Albert Hirsch, the alleged mastermind of Blackbriar program
CIA部门长官诺亚·沃森 计划实施的主管
and CIA Deputy Director Noah Vosen, the program's operational chief.
同时戴维·韦伯 或者说杰森·伯恩的下落
Meanwhile, mystery surrounds the fate of David Webb,
依然是个迷
also known as Jason Bourne, the source
他是揭露"黑石楠"计划的关键人物
behind the exposure of the Blackbriar program.
据报道韦伯被击中 从曼哈顿的10楼屋顶
It's been reported that Webb was shot and fell from a Manhattan rooftop
坠入纽约东河
into the East River ten stories below.
但是经过三天的搜寻
However, after a threeday search,
韦伯的尸体仍然没有被找到
Webb's body has yet to be found.